<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>2001 Enumeration District</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Layer identifies enumeration districts for the 2001 census. EDs were derived from the 2011 enumeration districts file and reverted back to the 2001 eds using orthorectified imagery and help from the Grenada Census Department. ED boundaries were manually shifted to line up along road and river boundaries where they appeared shifted. A description of each census field can be found in the Field and Subtypes part of the metadata.</abstract>
      <purpose>Developed for the 2001 census. Resource developed to help summarize all the raw census information that was used to calculate the socioeconomic indices. This information will help inform the Nature Conservancy's AWE project. Scientists around the world agree that climate change is indisputable. Impacts, including rising sea levels, increased storm intensity, warming temperatures and acidifying waters, dying coral reefs, shifting fish stocks, and incidence of flooding and drought, are already being felt, and are expected to continue and increase for decades to come. Nature holds some of the world’s best and most practical solutions to climate change, solutions that keep nature and people healthy, safe, and secure. The goal of At the Water’s Edge (AWE) is to demonstrate that governments and people in vulnerable coastal communities in Grenada and St. Vincent and the Grenadines (SVG) can enhance their resilience to climate change by protecting, restoring and effectively managing their marine and coastal ecosystems (also known as ecosystem-based adaptation or EBA) and strengthening local capacity for adaptation.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-61.802482</westbc>
        <eastbc>-61.378025</eastbc>
        <northbc>12.531896</northbc>
        <southbc>11.982904</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). By using this information, you agree to these terms. </useconst>
    <datacred>Created by Grenada Census Department and TNC. Data collected from the Grenada Census Department.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.3.3600</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>286</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-63.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu />
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>grd_poli_edcensusraw_2001</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ED_ID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>3-4 digit ED identifier from 2001 census</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>KEY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>6 digit ED code consisting of 2 digit unique parish identifier and 4 digit parish code (creating using ED_ID and adding a zero to create 4 digit number where necessary)</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ED_KEY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>5-6 digit ED code consisting of 2 digit unique parish identifier and the 3-4 digit ED_ID</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_CTRY1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>3 letter country identifier</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_CTRY2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>4 digit country identifier, same as calling code</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique 2 digit parish identifier</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_ED</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique ED identifier consisting of 4 digit country code, and 6 digit Key</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PNAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Parish Name</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREASQM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of enumeration district in meters</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREASQKM</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of enumeration district in kilometers</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREASQMI</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of enumeration district miles</attrdef>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20120725</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>