<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Ports</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Layer identifies the location of ports (seaports) throughout Grenada along with the number of ship calls, type of facility, and the infrastructure type. Data was obtained from the Grenada Ports Authority for all ports except the fuel terminal at Grand Mal.  The data represent the time period 2009 - 2010. </abstract>
      <purpose>Developed to locate and visualize ports in Grenada. This information will help inform the Nature Conservancy's AWE project and the resilience of infrastructure during inundation events for Grenada. Scientists around the world agree that climate change is indisputable. Impacts, including rising sea levels, increased storm intensity, warming temperatures and acidifying waters, dying coral reefs, shifting fish stocks, and incidence of flooding and drought, are already being felt, and are expected to continue and increase for decades to come. Nature holds some of the world’s best and most practical solutions to climate change, solutions that keep nature and people healthy, safe, and secure. The goal of At the Water’s Edge (AWE) is to demonstrate that governments and people in vulnerable coastal communities in Grenada and St. Vincent and the Grenadines (SVG) can enhance their resilience to climate change by protecting, restoring and effectively managing their marine and coastal ecosystems (also known as ecosystem-based adaptation or EBA) and strengthening local capacity for adaptation.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-61.755223</westbc>
        <eastbc>-61.458743</eastbc>
        <northbc>12.484823</northbc>
        <southbc>12.046640</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Ports, Infrastructure</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). By using this information, you agree to these terms.</useconst>
    <datacred>Edited and updated by Jerry J Mitchell for The Nature Conservancy (2012).  Contact the Grenada Port Authority for more information.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.3.3600</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>5</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-63.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu />
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>grd_inf_ports_2012</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_CTRY1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Country Code 1 - 3 letter country identifier</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_CTRY2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Country Code 2 - 4 digit country identifier, same as calling code</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_PAR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Parish Code - Unique 2 digit parish identifier</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>T_ED</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique census enumeration district identifier consisting of 4 digit country code, and 6 digit key</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ISLAND</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of island where feature is located</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of port</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Designates a terminal type to each feature.  </attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>INFRASTRC</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Information on the type of infrastructure at each port such as pier or bouys.  </attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CALLS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Number of calls to the port for the time period listed in the "TIME_PER" field.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TIME_PER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The time period for call to port number.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>N_SLIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The number of slips.</attrdef>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PHONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The telephone number of the port.</attrdef>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtopt />
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20120429</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>